Marco Luigi Nocentini

Junior Level Web Developer

Junior Level Developer moderately proficient in JavaScript, React and Redux with knowledge of PHP, HTML and Wordpress.

Applied programming skills in a ten years experience as Entrepreneur in online retail sales. Built and managed E-commerce websites, implemented personalized extensions, custom plugins, data analysis and automated tasks.

Ready to master new programming languages, software packages and technologies to achieve company objectives and improve performance and productivity. Eager to secure entry-level Junior Developer position and ready to help team achieve company goals.

Four years living abroad enhanced interpersonal skills in multicultural environments. One Year experience as Team Leader of a four people group in a sales company with responsibilities as trainer and motivator.

Experiences

Sept 2022 to Present

Currently Retraining as Full Time Web Developer

- Refocusing career path integrating ten years experience of developing websites to be more competitive and apply latest technologies and features.
- Following professional courses to improve proficiency in JavaScript, React and Redux development.

2012-2022 Ecommerce Developer & Team Manager

Self-Employed

- Created e-commerces using WordPress, PHP and HTML, CSS.
 Implemented required new features and personalized extensions and plugins. Developed PHP, and JavaScript features as needed. Created
- personalized back-end to automatically handle orders, new product listings and custom email replies.
- Managed team of employees (2), oversaw hiring, training and professional growth of employees.
- Resolved teamwork problems, improved operations, and created a friendly environment for employees.
- Handled customer inquiries and concerns, pre/post-sale, using PHP auto generated reply templates. Identified issues, analyzed information , and provided solutions to customer's problems.

2011 Sales Representative and Team Leader

Mondolibri

- Team Leader of a four people Group.
- Organized work, led by example, coached, and trained new assets, motivated team, solved problems.

2010 Software and Hardware Assistance

Notebook Service

- Interfaced with clients to understand and solve problems.
- Repaired computers analyzing issues and finding solutions.

2008-2009 Retail Sales Representative - Software Assistance

Euronics Store

 Helped clients with sales and software assistance, provided information about products.

Education

2000-09 -2005-06

High School Diploma

ITIS "Galileo Galilei" - Arezzo

• Completed professional development in "Computer and Electronic".

2005-10 -2008-04

Automation Engineering

Siena University - Siena / Arezzo

Completed 90/180 credits towards a degree in Automation

Engineering. Most Notable Completed Courses:

Linear Algebra, Mathematical Analysis I, Mathematical Analysis II, Physics I, Physics II, Fundamentals of Computer Science, Operational Research, Statistics, Electrical Engineering, Telecommunications.



Contacts

Address: 52100, Arezzo, Italy

Phone: +39 3711522792

E-mail: marco.luigi.nocentini@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/noce86

GitHub: https://github.com/Demandred86

Portfolio: https://marco-nocentini.netlify.app

Hard & Soft Skills

JavaScript

React

Redux

CSS

HTML

PHP

• GIT

WordPress

OOP

Organization & Time Management

Dependable & Responsible

Teamwork & Collaboration

Problem-solving

Critical thinking

Team building

Languages

English - Fluent Italian - Native

Recent Training Courses

Modern React with Redux

Clean Code for JavaScript

Master the Coding Interview Data Structures + Algorithms

JavaScript Advanced Concepts and Algorithms

The Complete JavaScript Course 2023

Java and Angular Developer Certificate

Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS

Autorizzo il trattamento dei miei dati personali ai sensi del Dlgs 196 del 30 giugno 2003 e dell'art. 13 GDPR